- Online music is close to a $30 billion industry.
And if you think about it, it's kind of a strange business.
A lot of times you can buy the same songs
from Apple Music, Spotify, or Tidal.
So why would you want to sign up for one service
over the other?
For most people, this has to do with the power
of their recommendation system.
A lot of these systems started off
by using unsupervised machine learning.
They would recommend songs the same ways
that online retailers would say things
were frequently bought together.
But the best music libraries
don't just want you to buy things together,
many of them want you to discover something new.
So for that,
you have to use a different form of machine learning.
This from of machine learning is called
Reinforcement Learning.
These are machine learning algorithms
that use rewards as a way to give the system incentive
to find new patterns.
A few years ago,
Google used Reinforcement Learning
to teach artificial intelligence systems
how to play video games.
Their AI systems beat expert players at Pong, Atari,
and even more modern video games.
But reinforcement learning
can do much more than just play video games.
These systems can improve over time,
by setting a series of goals and rewards.
Think of it this way,
Spotify Discover Weekly compares your favorite songs
with a bunch of related songs.
The machine learning algorithm tracks
every time you click and play a song.
It also keeps track of how long you listen.
The data scientists design the algorithms
so that every time you click a related song,
it gets a tiny digital reward.
It's almost like money for the machine learning system.
It gets this reward coin
when you click on the recommended song.
Then the longer you listen, the more the reward increases,
so it gets a reward coin for every minute
that you listen to the song.
These algorithms often use something called Q-Learning.
This type of reinforcement learning helps create
more sophisticated rewards.
In Q-Learning, there are set environments or states,
there are also possible actions
that can respond to the states.
In Q Learning, you want the machine to improve
the quality of the outcome,
which is represented by the letter Q.
In this case, you'd start with a Q of zero.
Then you'd have the machine learn the actions
that improve its conditions.
The state of Q would go up each time you clicked a song.
You can almost think of Q-Learning
like the system's bank account.
It can earn a bunch of coins and then see the balance grow.
Once the reward system is set up,
it'll look for patterns to try an increase
its Q-Learning bank account.
So if it sees a pattern where people who like one song
might listen to another, it'll exploit that
and make sure to put that song on your Discover Weekly.
Reinforcement learning systems work best
when your organization wants to do more
than just cluster items that are frequently bought together.
With Reinforcement Learning,
your organization can build a system that thinks creatively
about what your customer can discover.