- If you've ever worked as a product manager
or a software developer,
then you know that applications
need very explicit instructions.
Every time you open Microsoft Windows
or open an app on your iPhone,
you're benefiting from a programmer
coding the input and output.
But we've seen that this type of programming
doesn't work well with artificial intelligence.
There's too many combinations
to tie every input to an output.
In these cases, you need a programming model
that allows the machine to learn.
You also must give the machine
some ability to respond to feedback.
Imagine you're creating a program
that detects spam messages.
These messages are filled with
unwanted advertisements or viruses.
You could easily program a word filter
that deletes messages with common spam words.
If you frequently get messages
on entering contests,
you can filter words like,
gold, lottery or winner.
So you can program that,
"If the message contains gold,
then treat the message as spam."
But complex challenges
don't work well when you're limited
to programmed instructions.
That's why machine learning switches this around.
Instead of inputting instructions,
you're inputting data.
Instead of a program response,
you let the machine learn
from the patterns it identifies.
You can start with supervised machine learning.
Here, you need to split your data
into a training set and a test set.
The training data is a smaller chunk of data
that the machine uses to learn.
The system will use machine learning algorithms.
These algorithms rely on statistics.
You'll see a bunch of these
machine learning algorithms later on.
These algorithms help the machine
find relationships within the data.
So the machine uses an algorithm that
if the email message contains
the word lucky winner or congratulations,
then it's 50% more likely to be spam.
Then once the algorithm is accurate enough,
you can use what the system learn
on a larger test data set.
This test data is usually many times larger
than the data that the machine used to train.
Let's think about how machine learning
might work with our spam detection program.
We'll set aside 10,000 email messages
for our training set.
We'll use it to build our model.
This training data has 9,000 regular messages,
and 1000 messages labeled as spam.
We'll also set aside a million messages
for our test data.
This test data is unlabeled.
That means that it's unlike our training set,
no one has correctly labeled
any of the messages is spam.
That would be a lot of work
for a million messages.
Your training data is then used
to let the machine identify the spam messages.
Then once the machine learning algorithm
gets close to identifying
the thousand spam messages,
you'll try it on the larger test data set.
Once you're satisfied,
that will be your initial data model.
Now, this machine learning algorithm
only has two options.
Is that a regular message or a spam message?
That's why this is called,
a Binary Classification Challenge.
You'll only need to classify your email message
into one or two groups.
This is one of the most common uses
for machine learning.
The key thing to remember is that,
machine learning algorithms use statistics
to find patterns in your data.
Once your machine identifies these patterns,
it can then classify your data
based on what it's learned.