- Another common machine learning algorithm
is K-means clustering.
K-means clustering is an unsupervised
machine learning algorithm.
It's used to create clusters
based on what your machine sees in the data.
Let's go back to the animal shelter in Chicago.
The shelter used to have a large social room
where the dogs got together, sniffed and played.
The dogs had their group of friends
and they played and hung out together.
Each time they had a social hour,
they would self-organize into these social groups.
Now imagine that the shelter was closing
and all the dogs were going to be distributed
to three different shelters.
To make it easier for the dogs,
the organizers decided to cluster the dogs
based on their friend groups.
So the shelter created three clusters.
That means the K in K-means equaled three,
because they wanted to divide the groups
into three clusters.
To start, the machine put a red, yellow or blue
colored collar on three random dogs.
Each color represented a potential cluster
based on their social group.
These would be your three centroid dogs.
Each of the centroid dogs
would look at the mean or average distance
between itself and all of the surrounding dogs.
Then the machine would put the same colored collar
on the dogs that were closest to a centroid.
Since these centroid dogs were selected randomly
there was a pretty good chance
that they wouldn't really have any good clusters.
Maybe all three centroid dogs were in the same social group.
If that happened, then most of the dogs would be far away
from their nearest centroid,
so it would redistribute collars
until the algorithm could find a good centroid dog.
The machine would try over and over again
until it picked the best centroid
and it might even do this one cluster at a time.
At the end of each iteration,
the machine learning algorithm checked the variance
between each dog and the centroid.
Once there was a good centroid,
then it would put the same color collars
on the friends of the dogs in each cluster.
Now, keep in mind that the dogs themselves
did not cluster into three groups.
There might be seven or eight different social groups
but there were only three shelters,
so the algorithm had to do its best to cluster the dogs'
natural social grouping.
The algorithm also had to consider very social dogs
that jump from group to group.
If the dogs were moving around too much,
then it'd be difficult to form real clusters.
Another challenge with k-means
is it can be very sensitive to outliers.
So if you had a dog that wasn't hanging out with other dogs
it would still have to be clustered
into one of these three groups.
Essentially, the dog would be forced to find friends.
Organizing dogs into three clusters
for three different shelters is probably not a problem
you'll run into every day.
But K-means clustering is one of the most
popular machine learning algorithms.
One of the more interesting applications
is when retailers use clustering to decide
who gets promotions.
They might have the system create three clusters
to find loyal customers, regular customers
and lowest price shoppers.
Then they'll create strategies to elevate regular customers
into loyal customers.
Many organizations are looking for better ways
to cluster together their customers.
If they can get all of their loyal customers
into one cluster,
then they can really improve their business.
K-means clustering is a good way for the system
to cluster people or things
by looking at hundreds of different variables.