- So what does it take to build an AI system?
To think about this, let's go back to our challenge
of finding dogs in images.
The first step data scientists need to do,
is figure out what they want from the data.
In this case, they're not asking the AI system
to cluster together its own groups.
Instead, they're asking the system
to classify data into two categories.
One category will have images with dogs
and the others will be not dogs.
This is a classic binary classification challenge.
Remember, that's when the neural network
just has two possible classifications.
This means they'll be doing supervised machine learning.
Remember that supervised machine learning
starts out with labeled data.
Here, the system will be trained
with hundreds of thousands of images known to contain dogs.
The next step for data scientists
is to figure out if they want to use
standard machine learning algorithms,
or if they'd like to use an artificial neural network.
Remember that this is a classification problem,
so if they go with machine learning algorithms,
they'll probably either use K nearest neighbor
or naive bayes.
You've seen that the system
will break down each image into pixels.
That means that this is going to be a complex challenge
with a lot of data,
so they're going to use an artificial neural network.
They'll create the input layer,
hidden layers and output layer.
Now, remember that since
this is a binary classification challenge,
there are only two options, dog or not dog,
so they'll need just two nodes for the output layer.
Next, the neural network will be initialized.
The system will assign random numbers
to all the weights of the connections.
Then, the system will set the bias on all the nodes to zero.
This is almost like shaking an etch a sketch
to give itself a clean slate.
Now, the training set needs to be fed
into the neural network.
The first few images will probably be not that much better
than random guesses.
The neural network will say something like,
there's a 62% chance that the image contains a dog,
or a 55% chance it's not.
Then, the network will compare its answer
to the label on the data.
If it misidentifies the dog image,
then it will look at the gradient descent
to determine how much to change the weights and biases.
The neural network will go through
all the data in your training set to fine tune its results.
Remember that the network will tune itself
by using backpropagation to change the weights and bias
to lower the cost function.
In a sense, it will go backward through the network
and twist all the dials to increase its accuracy.
Once the artificial neural network
has gone through the training set,
then data will be added from the test set.
The test set will not be labeled.
It could be hundreds of thousands of images of anything.
Then you'll see how well your neural network performed
when identifying dog photos.
Sometimes, the neural network
will do very well with the training set,
but not so well with the test set.
When this happens, it usually means
that you are overfitting the data.
Remember, that's when the system's really good
at identifying the smaller training set
but doesn't have enough complexity
to deal with the new data in the test set.
Now, it's unlikely that your team
will classify dog, or not dog, anytime soon.
However, this approach to binary classification
is a powerful way to get insights from your data.
Think about your customer data, your sales data,
or even data from your IOT devices
and what you can learn from this approach.