- Imagine a computer that didn't need to be programmed.
The system could learn the same way you do just
by observing the world.
You've seen that earlier AI systems
used a symbolic approach.
The idea was that if the system recognized symbols
then it would start to seem intelligent.
One of the key challenges was
that programmers worked with experts to create the system.
That's why they were called expert systems.
Later, computer scientists gave up
on this approach because it created too many combinations.
They decided
that you couldn't just program intelligence into a system
but maybe you could program a system to become intelligent
through observation.
It wouldn't feel, hear or see or taste like a human.
Instead, it would learn by sensing data.
In 1959, a computer scientist named Arthur Samuel
created a checkers program that could learn
by playing against itself.
It played both sides
of the board and taught itself strategy through observation.
The more the machine played
the more it saw patterns on how to win.
Computer scientists didn't program the machine
to play checkers.
It learned through its own experience.
Arthur Samuel's called this idea machine learning.
This was different from symbolic systems.
No human program the moves and counter moves.
Instead, the system was designed to learn
and improve on its own.
The system would quickly learn new checker strategies
and after a short period of time
it consistently beat its programmer.
Machine learning was a breakthrough discovery.
There was only one downside.
These systems could play games, but in the 1950s
there wasn't that much digital data.
Remember that machine learning uses data as its five senses.
So without data, it could only find the simplest patterns
but that all changed.
At the beginning of the 1990s, the explosion
of the internet suddenly had everyday people
creating huge amounts of data.
The 1990s was a time
of explosive growth for machine learning systems.
The new data was like water that poured
over the dry fields of artificial intelligence.
At this point, machine learning systems had
the fuel they needed to become more intelligent.
So if you wanted to teach the system on how to
identify a cat, you had access to millions
of cat pictures online.
Computer scientists began to
create newer machine learning algorithms.
There were even some researchers that started to
create systems that were designed to mimic the human brain.
One of the big advantages of learning through data is
that machines could continue to grow with more data.
If the machine finds new patterns
it can adapt to the new information.
But it's important to keep in mind
that you still run into some of the same challenges.
The machine learning system is still just
identifying patterns.
Still, in the last few years
machine learning has been the fastest growing area in AI.
As the amount of data increases
This area has even shown more promise.
Organizations are constantly collecting vast amounts
of new data.
So now the big challenge has become figuring out
what to do with all this information.
In a sense, you have artificial intelligence systems looking
through your data
and letting your organization see what it finds.