- Today, there are thermostats, doorbells,
and televisions that connect with each other and the world.
And there are smartwatches that check your location
and some even upload medical data.
This new way of connecting
is commonly called the internet of things.
Sometimes you'll see it as IoT for short.
IoT devices are objects with sensors
that communicate with the outside world.
They typically upload data through the internet.
IoT devices are a massive new source of data.
They can upload their locations,
so that means that if you are wearing an IoT device
then these machine learning systems
can see patterns in where you travel.
They can accurately predict where you work,
shop, eat, watch, and who you visit.
Maybe your smartwatch will tell your thermostat
when you're on the way home.
IoT also allows these devices
to communicate with each other.
They could unlock your doors
or have your computer turn on when you sit at your desk.
In some ways, these new devices make it easier
to create data than it is for humans to analyze.
That's why many IoT companies invest heavily in AI.
AI not only allows organizations to see new patterns,
it also allows them to quickly react.
IoT devices and artificial intelligence
are a powerful combination
that allow companies to create systems
that predict people's behavior.
My family purchased one of the earliest versions
of Amazon's Alexa home assistant.
It was a terrific and simple clock,
but early on my wife noticed
that the Amazon recommendation list
was becoming populated with things
that were part of our conversations.
We once talked about visiting a relative in Rome
that a few days later,
a travel guide to Rome popped up
in our Amazon recommended list.
Ring doorbells also collect data
on people who walk in front of your house.
The company can use machine learning for facial recognition.
It can then use your doorbell
to create a vast surveillance network
that's sold to police departments.
These departments can use this data
to place people at the scene of a crime
or locate people they're interested in finding.
One area that has a lot of growth is IoT medical devices.
You can now purchase a smartwatch that's as accurate
as your doctor's electrocardiogram or EKG.
They can use the sensors to detect any health issues.
Then they can upload that data to their servers.
Companies like Apple look for patterns in EKG data
using machine learning on a neural network.
Their network can go through millions of participants.
They can use this data to find patterns
to accurately predict any health issues.
It's certainly helpful to have machines find
predictable patterns.
Maybe they'll find that people are more likely
to have health issues on Wednesdays.
They can also see patterns
that affect large groups of people.
You could see something like air pollution
and its effect on the city's health.
In many ways, the IoT devices take the strength
of machine learning in the digital world
and put it in the realm of the physical world.
Instead of just seeing what you're doing online,
an IoT device can track your behavior offline.
This has enormous potential for organizations
to sell your products based on
what you need and where you go.