- In this course, you got an overview
of the technology behind artificial intelligence.
You saw the field started with key concepts,
such as the general problem solver and symbolic reasoning.
Then you saw how machine learning got a slow start,
but then quickly became a dominant field in AI.
You got an overview of machine learning concepts
and technology.
You've seen how several different
machine learning algorithms can help learn
from massive data sets.
You also saw how artificial neural networks
could be used with machine learning to get deeper insights
and find complex patterns.
Finally, you saw how your network uses back propagation
to learn from its mistakes and improve its accuracy.
I hope that throughout the course,
you got a sense for how to apply
some of these technologies to help solve complex problems.
You should also think about some of the ethical challenges
behind AI.
Is it okay to have machines make decisions
about your health, welfare, and financial credit?
These decisions could come from a black box,
where you have no idea what the machine understood.
If you're interested in these issues,
I've also created a Data Ethics series,
which might be a good follow-up to this course.
As always, please feel free to follow me on LinkedIn.
There, you'll see articles and links
about artificial intelligence, data ethics,
and key business challenges.
Thank you for watching this introduction
to artificial intelligence.