- I once worked for a company that sold vehicles online.
Each time they sent a customer to an auto dealership
the company earned a referral fee.
For them, it was always about looking at trends
in auto sales.
People were much more likely to buy convertibles
and sports cars in the spring and summer.
Others were more likely to buy trucks
and SUVs in the fall and winter.
So when customers visited the website
they had seasonal promotions for what people wanted to buy.
One of the tools they used was regression analysis.
Regression analysis is a supervised machine
learning algorithm.
It looks at the relationship
between predictors and the outcome.
Sometimes you'll hear predictors called input variables,
independent variables, or even regressors.
Regression analysis is a supervised
machine learning algorithm.
You're taking the training data
and labeling the correct output.
Then you're using the labeled data with the test data.
The best way to think about regression is to imagine trends.
As the weather gets warmer
people are more likely to buy convertibles.
As the weather gets cooler
people are more likely to buy trucks and SUVs.
Regression analysis doesn't tell you why
people do these things.
This is for data scientists
and business analysts to figure out.
It just tells you that these things are happening.
Machine learning regression algorithms
work in a similar way.
Once you have your training data, you make a prediction
then see how close you are to the outcome.
Then you repeat over and over again
until the system makes the most accurate prediction.
In this case, the data science team thought
that the change of seasons would be a great predictor
for the sale of some vehicles.
So they put the months as a predictor.
Then they mapped that against the sales of certain vehicles.
With this training data,
they created a simple X and Y axis diagram.
Remember that this is the simple chart that you learned
from geometry.
Along the Y or bottom axis
they listed the names of the month,
and along the X or top axis,
they put the sales by vehicle type.
Then they looked at the trend line.
Convertibles and sports car sales would go up
in May, June, and July.
Then those sales would go down in September, October
and November.
For trucks and SUVs, it was the opposite.
The more data you have available, the easier it is to
make an accurate trend line.
As you can imagine, regression can be enormously powerful
for organizations.
You can make the product available
just as the customer's interested in buying.
That's why large retailers like Walmart famously
stock their shelves with items
just as their customers taste change.
People buy more Pop-Tarts in the summer
and they buy more milk and cheese in the winter.
They want to make sure that the shelves are filled
with these items based on predicted buying trends.
One interesting thing about regression analysis
is that there's some question about whether
it's true machine learning.
That makes sense
because the system isn't learning anything new.
It's less about learning and more about predicting.
Either way, regression is a very popular way
for businesses to predict future behavior.
And these trends are everywhere.
If you're missing them, you're not learning from them.
So take a moment to think
about where regression analysis might find trends
in your business.
What you learn might surprise you.