- Artificial intelligence systems are
now finding their way into the workplace.
These systems can discover new pharmaceuticals,
recommend products, detect fraud, and much more.
This course will give you a high-level overview
of artificial intelligence concepts and technology.
You'll see what it means for systems to be intelligent,
then discover some widely used machine learning algorithms
and artificial neural networks.
Many of those who interact
with these systems will be people just like you,
people in business, entrepreneurs, managers, or students.
Just as managers work with software developers today,
these same managers will work
with AI systems and data tomorrow.
So let's see what those machines have been up to
in the world of artificial intelligence.