- In 1956, computer scientists, Allen Newell
and Herbert A. Simon created a program
they called the general problem solver.
One of the key ideas of the general problem solver
was what they called the physical symbol system hypothesis.
They said that symbols were a big part
of how we interact with the world.
When you see a stop sign, you know how to stop for traffic.
When you see the letter A, you know that the word
will make a certain sound.
When you see a sandwich, you might think of eating.
They argued that if you could program a machine
to connect these symbols then it would be intelligent.
But not everyone bought into this idea.
If you program a car to stop at a sign,
or if you teach a computer to respond to language,
then it doesn't make the system intelligent.
In 1980, the philosopher John Searle explained
that sometimes systems can seem intelligent,
but they're just mindlessly matching patterns.
To explain, he created what he called
the Chinese room argument.
In the argument, you should imagine yourself
in a windowless room with one mail slot on the door.
You can only use this slot to communicate
with the outside world.
In the room, you have a phrase book on a desk and a bunch
of post-it notes with Chinese symbols on the floor.
The book shows what response you should use
with the note that comes through the slot.
It says, "If you see this sequence of Chinese symbols,
then respond with that sequence of Chinese symbols."
Now, imagine a speaker writes something in Chinese Mandarin
and pushes it through the slot.
You can look at the note and match it with your phrase book.
Then you paste together the Mandarin response
from the post-it notes on the floor.
You have no idea what it says in Mandarin.
Instead, you simply go through the process of looking
through the book and matching the sequence of symbols.
A native Chinese speaker behind the door might believe
that they're having a conversation.
In fact, they might even assume that the person
in the room is a native speaker.
But Searle argues that this is far from intelligence,
since the person in the room can't speak Mandarin,
and doesn't have any idea what they're talking about.
You can try a similar experiment with your smartphone.
Try asking Siri or Cortana how they feel.
They might say they feel fine, but that doesn't mean
that they're telling you how they really feel.
They also don't know what you're asking.
They're just matching your question
to a pre-program response,
just like the person in the Chinese room.
So Searle argues that matching symbols
is not a true path to intelligence.
That a computer is acting just like the person in the room.
They don't understand the meaning.
They're just matching patterns from a phrase book.
Even with these challenges, physical symbol systems
were still the cornerstone of AI for 25 years.
Yet, in the end, programming all these matching patterns
took up too much time.
It was impossible to match all the symbols
without running into an explosion of combinations.
These combinations would soon fill up
even the largest phrase book.
There were just too many possibilities to match symbols
with their program response.
So many philosophers like John Searle,
argued that the path would never lead to true intelligence.