- Machine learning has gotten a big boost
from artificial neural networks.
An artificial neural network is an AI system
that mimics the structure of the human brain
and it's currently one
of the most popular approaches to machine learning.
Think of it this way.
When I was a kid,
we used to play a game called animal, vegetable, or mineral.
The point of the game was simple.
Someone would think of an item.
Then all the other kids would ask questions
about what the item was.
We'd ask things like, does it have fur?
Is it bigger than a house?
Then in another round,
we'd ask if it's alive, does it make noise?
After each round, we would start to zoom in
to identify the item.
Then at the end, we started making guesses.
Is it a horse?
Is it a cat?
Is it a dog?
An artificial neural network uses a very similar approach,
except instead of asking questions,
the neural network uses hundreds
or even millions of numerical dials.
Also, the network makes much more specific guesses.
It would say that there's a 64% chance that it's a cat
or a 32% chance that it's a dog.
To build the network,
there's a row of neurons on the left called the input layer.
Then there's a row of neurons
on the right called the output layer.
All the neurons in between are called the hidden layers.
They're hidden because it's not the input or output.
To start, we'd feed the input layer of the network
a picture of a dog.
We know it's a picture of a dog because we've labeled it
but the neural network doesn't look
at these labels until it makes a guess.
Just like the animal, vegetable, mineral game.
The network would then look at each dot
in the image as it passes through the hidden layers.
Then it makes a guess for the output layer.
Let's say for the first guess,
it says there's a 10% chance the image contains a dog.
Then the network compares its guess
to the label on the image.
This is called training the neural network.
Then the network goes backwards and adjusts the neuron dials
so they can see patterns in dog photos.
Then it takes another dog image and sees if it gets closer.
The neural network then tunes itself
by looking at hundreds of thousands of pictures of dogs.
Then it will adjust its own dials
until it consistently guesses correctly.
Now, it's important to keep in mind
that the neural network
isn't seeing the dog the same way you do.
It doesn't think about panting, barking, or fur.
Instead, the system only sees the dog
as a recognizable pattern of dots in an image.
When there's dots in a dog-like pattern,
then the system makes a guess.
Now, remember that these neural networks
are still machine learning systems,
so the network needs access
to huge amounts of data.
If you don't have hundreds of thousands of pictures of dogs,
then there's no way
for that artificial neural network to learn.
In the end, this is the key benefit
of an artificial neural network.
It can train itself to understand patterns
and recognize that input when looking
through massive amounts of data.