- Machine learning is one
of the most popular areas in artificial intelligence.
That's partly because of the explosion of data
but it's also because of huge advances
in machine learning algorithms.
Machine learning on its own is just a set of techniques.
It's a way to build systems that learn through data.
They move beyond the early AI systems that needed
to be explicitly programmed.
But there isn't one big machine learning program
like Microsoft Office.
Instead, you have many different
machine learning algorithms.
Most of these algorithms are borrowed from statistics.
The key thing to remember is that each
of these algorithms are like a chef's kitchen tool.
Spoons are used for stirring
and knives are used for cutting, but sometimes,
chefs can find new creative uses for that tool.
Some chefs use the side
of their knife to crush a garlic clove
or use a spoon to twirl spaghetti.
I once worked for a company
that was using credit card data to try
and come up with customer promotions.
They started out using supervised machine learning
to classify the customers into two different groups.
Remember, this is called binary classification.
The first group of customers used promotions
and the second group never used them.
Then they used machine learning algorithms
to train the system on this binary classification.
Once they classified their customers into these two groups,
they used unsupervised machine learning.
They wanted to see if they could learn something
about their customers who used promotions
so they let the machine create clusters
of this specific customer.
Remember that unsupervised machine learning
lets the system create its own clusters based
on the patterns that it sees in the data.
It's the same way that my son found clusters
in unknown candy.
What they found was that within this group
who used promotions, there was an even smaller group
of customers who always used promotions.
They called them the promotions super users.
Since this company was paid based on the success
of its promotions, this was a great group to know.
They found that this group used promotions for products,
services, and restaurants.
Those customers just love saving money,
so the company tweaked the algorithm
to offer more promotions to these promotions super users.
That small change helped boost their overall success rate.
Now, this organization used both supervised
and unsupervised machine learning,
so you'll have some algorithms
that work best with supervised classifying
and other algorithms that work best
with unsupervised clustering.
That's why it's important to see some
of the machine learning algorithms that are available.
Each one has its own strengths and weaknesses.
Some take up more processing power while others are lighter
and less accurate.
Each algorithm is primarily used for either supervised
or unsupervised learning, but there are algorithms
that you can use for both.
Like any good chef, the true creativity
is not the tools, the ingredients.
Your data science team might want to mix
and match these algorithms to gain the greatest insights
from your data.
These machine learning algorithms are available
in most of the machine learning software toolkits
so it's here where your data science team can use its skill
and creativity.